Guide to the John William Davis Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1921-1923; Series III; 4.5 linear feet (11 boxes)
  - Select correspondence
    - Wardwell, Allen, 1923 (Box 19, Folder 108)
    - Warren, Charles, 1922-1923 (Box 19, Folder 108)
    - Washington and Lee University, 1921-1923 (Box 19, Folder 109)
      See: box 8, folder 7
    - Watson, Clarence Wayland, 1923 (Box 19, Folder 110)
    - Watts, Harvey Maitland, 1922 (Box 19, Folder 110)
    - Wehle, Louis Brandeis, 1921 (Box 19, Folder 110)
    - Wickersham, George Woodward, 1922-1933 (Box 19, Folder 110)
      See also: box 14, folder 3 See also: box 16, folder 40 See also: box 17, folders 53-60 See also: box 17, folders 63-65 See also: box 18, folder 85
    - Wiley, Louis, 1922-1923 (Box 19, Folder 111)
    - Wright, J. Butler, 1921-1922 (Box 19, Folder 111)
    - Yale University, 1921-1922 (Box 19, Folder 111)
  - General correspondence
    - 1921 March 16-April (Box 19, Folder 112)
    - 1921 May-1922 March (Box 20, Folder 113-122)
    - 1922 April-October (Box 21, Folder 123-131)
    - 1922 November-1923 March (Box 22, Folder 132-139)
    - 1923 April-September (Box 23, Folder 140-148)
    - 1923 October-December (Box 24, Folder 149-152)
  - Financial correspondence
    - 1921 March 16 - 1923 (Box 24, Folder 153-155)
- Correspondence, 1924-1955; Series IV; 51 linear feet (121 boxes)
  The overall arrangement is chronological, with secondary order as follows: day-to-day chronological, 1924-1936; mixture of day-to-day chronological with alphabetical by year, 1937-1939; alphabetical by year, 1940-1955. There is additional correspondence from this period filed by topic in Series VII, VIII, and XI, and some letters in this series are also available arranged by topic or correspondent on Hist. Mss. Misc. film 84.
  For a partial index to correspondents in this series, see the catalogs listed in this register.
  - 1924 January - February 15 (Box 25)
  - 1924 February 16 - April 1 (Box 26)
  - 1924 April 2 - 30 (Box 27)
  - 1924 May - June 2 (Box 28)
  - 1924 June 3 - 30 (Box 29)
  - 1924 July 1 - 17 (Box 30)
  - 1924 July 18 - August 5 (Box 31)
  - 1924 August 6 - 23 (Box 32)
  - 1924 August 24 - October 8 (Box 33)
  - 1924 October 9-November 6 (Box 34)
  - 1924 November 7-30 (Box 35)
  - 1924 December - 1925 February 20 (Box 36)
  - 1925 February 21 - April 8 (Box 37)
  - 1925 April 9-May 16 (Box 38)
  - 1925 May 17-July 2 (Box 39)
  - 1925 July 3-September 8 (Box 40)
  - 1925 September 9-November 5 (Box 41)
  - 1925 November 6-December (Box 42)
  - 1926 January-March 5 (Box 43)
  - 1926 March 6-April (Box 44)
  - 1926 May-July 5 (Box 45)
  - 1926 July 6-October 3 (Box 46)
  - 1926 October 4-November (Box 47)
  - 1926 December - 1927 January (Box 48)
  - 1927 February - April 5 (Box 49)
  - 1927 April 6 - June 10 (Box 50)
  - 1927 June 11 - September (Box 51)
  - 1927 October - December 3 (Box 52)
  - 1927 December 4 - 1928 February 8 (Box 53)
  - 1928 February 9 - April 5 (Box 54)
  - 1928 April 6 - June 10 (Box 55)
  - 1928 June 11 - 1928 September 5 (Box 56)
  - 1928 September 6 - October 20 (Box 57)
  - 1928 October 21 - December 13 (Box 58)
  - 1928 December 14 - 1929 February 7 (Box 59)
  - 1929 February 8 - April 4 (Box 60)
  - 1929 April 5 - May (Box 61)
  - 1929 June - September 11 (Box 62)
  - 1929 September 12 - November 13 (Box 63)
  - 1929 November 14 - 1930 January 15 (Box 64)
  - 1930 January 16 - March 8 (Box 65)
  - 1930 March 10 - April 18 (Box 66)
  - 1930 April 19 - June 7 (Box 67)
  - 1930 June 9 - August (Box 68)
  - 1930 September - October 24 (Box 69)
  - 1930 October 25 - December 10 (Box 70)
  - 1930 December 11 - 1931 January (Box 71)
  - 1931 February - March (Box 72)
  - 1931 April - June 1 (Box 73)
  - 1931 June 2 - August 16 (Box 74)
  - 1931 August 17 - October 6 (Box 75)
  - 1931 October 7 - November 10 (Box 76)
  - 1931 November 11 - December 9 (Box 77)
  - 1931 December 10 - 1932 January 11 (Box 78)
  - 1932 January 12 - February 10 (Box 79)
  - 1932 February 11 - March 17 (Box 80)
  - 1932 March 18 - April 16 (Box 81)
  - 1932 April 17 - May 23 (Box 82)
  - 1932 May 24 - July 8 (Box 83)
  - 1932 July 9 - September 16 (Box 84)
  - 1932 September 17 - October 21 (Box 85)
  - 1932 October 22 - November 19 (Box 86)
  - 1932 November 20 - December 20 (Box 87)
  - 1932 December 21 - 1933 January 26 (Box 88)
  - 1933 January 27 - March 1 (Box 89)
  - 1933 March 2 - April 16 (Box 90)
  - 1933 April 17 - June 15 (Box 91)
  - 1933 June 16 - September 15 (Box 92)
  - 1933 September 16 - December 7 (Box 93)
  - 1933 December 8 - 1934 February (Box 94)
  - 1934 March - May 12 (Box 95)
  - 1934 May 13 - July 18 (Box 96)
  - 1934 July 19 - October 4 (Box 97)
  - 1934 October 5 - December 12 (Box 98)
  - 1934 December 13 - 1935 February 11 (Box 99)
  - 1935 February 12 - April 18 (Box 100)
  - 1935 April 19 - June (Box 101)
  - 1935 July - October 12 (Box 102)
  - 1935 October 13 - December 9 (Box 103)
  - 1935 December 10 - 1936 January (Box 104)
  - 1936 February - March 29 (Box 105)
  - 1936 March 30 - June 3 (Box 106)
  - 1936 June 4 - September 20 (Box 107)
  - 1936 September 21 - November 12 (Box 108)
  - 1936 November 17 - 1937 April 7 (Box 109)
    See also: boxes 116-118
  - 1937 April 8 - November 25 (Box 110)
  - 1937 November 26 - 1938 May 15 (Box 111)
    See also: See also: boxes 116-120
  - 1938 May 16 - December 31 (Box 112)
    See also: boxes 118-120
  - 1939 January - April (Box 113)
    See also: boxes 120-121
  - 1939 May - August (Box 114)
  - 1939 September - December (Box 115)
    See also: boxes 121-121
  - 1937 A - F (Box 116)
    See also: boxes 109-111
  - 1937 G - N (Box 117)
  - 1937 O - Z (Box 118)
  - 1938 A - C (Box 118)
    See also: boxes 111-112
  - 1938 C (cont'd) - G (Box 119)
  - 1938 H - Z (Box 120)
  - 1939 A - C (Box 120)
    See also: boxes 113-115
  - 1939 D - Z (Box 121)
  - 1940 A - D (Box 121)
  - 1940 E - M (Box 122)
  - 1940 N - Z (Box 123)
  - 1941 A - L (Box 124)
  - 1941 M - Z (Box 125)
  - 1942 A (Box 125)
  - 1942 B - N (Box 126)
  - 1942 O- Z (Box 127)
  - 1943 A - F (Box 127)
  - 1943 G - Z (Box 128)
  - 1944 A - K (Box 129)
  - 1944 L - Z (Box 130)
  - 1945 A - B (Box 130)
  - 1945 C - M (Box 131)
  - 1945 N - Z (Box 132)
  - 1946A-B (Box 132)
  - 1946 C - N (Box 133)
  - 1946 O - Z (Box 134)
  - 1947 A - C (Box 134)
  - 1947 D - R (Box 135)
  - 1947 S - Z (Box 136)
  - 1948-1949 A - C (Box 136)
  - 1948-1949 C (cont'd) - K (Box 137)
  - 1948-1949 L - S (Box 138)
  - 1948-1949 T - Z (Box 139)
  - 1950 A - G (Box 139)
  - 1950 H - Z (Box 140)
  - 1951 A - S (Box 141)
  - 1951 T-Z (Box 142)
  - 1952 A - H (Box 142)
  - 1952 I - Z (Box 143)
  - 1953 (Box 143)
  - 1954-1955 (Box 144)
  - Unidentified, 1940-1955 (Box 144)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 144)
  - Undated (Box 144)
  - Condolences on Davis's death (Box 145)
- Presidential Campaign, 1924; Series V; 4 linear feet (10 boxes)
  Memoranda and research material are in alphabetical order. Newspaper clippings and speeches are in separate chronological sequences. There are photographs in Series XI.
  - Publications (Box 146)
  - Strategy material (Box 146)
  - Memoranda and research material
    - Agriculture (Box 147)
    - Conservation (Box 147)
    - Education (Box 148)
    - Foreign affairs (general) (Box 148)
    - Foreign affairs (topical) (Box 149)
    - Government regulation of industry (Box 149)
    - Labor (Box 149)
    - Law enforcement (Box 149)
    - Religious and racial toleration (Box 149)
    - Republican platform (Box 150)
    - Tariff (Box 150)
    - Taxation (Box 151)
    - Veterans (Box 151)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 151)
  - Press releases and interviews (Box 151)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - January - July (Box 151)
    - August - November (Box 152)
    - Italian and Swedish (Box 152)
  - Biographical sketches and published accounts of Davis, LaFollette, and Charles W. Bryan (Box 152)
  - Speeches
    - August 11 - October 7 (Box 153)
    - October 8 - 31 (Box 154)
    - November 1 - 3 (Box 155)
    - Fragments and notes (Box 155)
    - Unidentified (Box 155)
    - Postcard responses to speech at Hastings, Nebraska, Sep 6 (Box 155)
    - Speakers other than Davis (Box 155)
- Speeches and Writings, 1897-1955; Series VI; 2 linear feet (6 boxes)
  The arrangement is chronological.
  - 1897-1922 (Box 156)
  - 1923-1924 July (Box 157)
  - 1924 August-December (Box 157)
    See: box 146
  - 1938 May-1946 (Box 158)
  - 1947-1955 (Box 159)
  - undated (Box 160)
  - undated (Box 161)
- Law Practice, 1913-[1950s?]; Series VII; 3.5 linear feet (4 boxes)
  These papers are essentially unprocessed.
  - Correspondence (by case) (Box 162)
  - Briefs, transcripts, memoranda (Box 163)
  - Supreme Court documents
    - 1913 - 1916 (Box 164)
    - 1917 - 1918 (Box 165)
- Civic and Professional Activities, Circa 1928-1954; Series VIII; 7 linear feet (7 boxes)
  The arrangement is alphabetical, with minor material grouped by type of organization at the end of the series.
  - American Bar Association (Box 166)
  - American Foundation (Box 166)
  - American Law Institute (Box 167)
  - American Liberty League (Box 167)
  - Carnegie Endowment (includes Alger Hiss) (Box 168)
  - Carnegie Foundation (Box 168)
  - Citizens Emergency Committee (Box 169)
  - Committee on Federal-State Relations (Box 169)
  - Constitutional Amendments (Box 169)
  - Democratic party (Box 169)
  - English-Speaking Union (Box 169)
  - Foreign Policy Association (Box 169)
  - Harvard - International law (Box 170)
  - Hughes memorial resolutions (Box 170)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations (Box 170)
  - Joint Committee on Legal Education in the State of New York (Box 170)
  - New York County Lawyers' Association (Box 170)
  - New York State Reorganization Committee (Box 170)
  - Pierpont Morgan Library (Box 170)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 171)
  - U.S. Chamber of Commerce (Box 172)
  - Washington and Lee University (Box 172)
  - Medical boards (Box 172)
  - Clubs, societies (Box 172)
  - Directorships (Box 172)
  - Congressional business (Box 172)
- Harbaugh Biography, Circa 1960s; Series IX; 5 linear feet (5 boxes)
  The arrangement is by chapter.
  - Notes, drafts, and research material (includes copies of letters for which the originals are in Series IV)
    - Chapters 1 - 8 (Box 173)
    - Chapters 9 - 13, 1924 campaign (Box 174)
    - 1924 campaign (cont'd), Chapters 14 - 21 (Box 175)
    - Chapters 22 - 24 (Box 176)
    - Chapters 25 - 29 (Box 177)
  - Law review articles (Box 177)
  - Miscellany (Box 177)
  - Photographs (Accession 94-M-89) (Box 177)
- Writings of Others, 1863-(1920-1959); Series X; 3 linear feet (3 boxes)
  - 1900 - 1930 (Box 178)
  - 1931 - 1939 (Box 179)
  - 1940 - 1959, undated (Box 180)
- Personal and Miscellaneous papers, 1870-(1898-1958); Series XI; 6.5 linear feet (17 boxes, 1 folio)
  The papers are grouped by physical type. The clippings and miscellaneous papers are in chronological order. The photographs are arranged by subject.
  - Subject file
    - Financial (Box 181)
    - Health (Box 182)
    - Eightieth birthday (Box 182)
    - Long Island property (Box 182)
    - Mallory-Phillips case (boy killed by JWD's chauffeur) (Box 182)
    - John J. Davis estate (Box 182)
    - Parodies and other humorous writings (Box 182)
  - Miscellany and memorabilia (Box 183)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 184)
  - Biographical material (Box 184)
  - Datebooks (Box 185)
  - Small and medium size photographs
    - JWD and family
      - JWD (Box 186)
      - JWD (from Harbaugh's book files) (Box 186)
      - JWD and Mrs. John W. Davis (Box 186)
      - Mrs. John W. Davis (Ellen G. Bassell) and others (Box 186)
      - Davis family groupings (Box 186)
      - Anna (Kennedy) Davis (JWD's mother) (Box 186)
      - John J. Davis (JWD's father) (Box 186)
      - Julia (McDonald) Davis (JWD's first wife) (Box 186)
      - Julia McDonald Davis (JWD's daughter) (Box 186)
      - Julia (Leavell) McDonald (mother of JWD's first wife) (Box 186)
      - Lillie, Nannie, and Emma Davis (JWD's sisters) (Box 186)
      - Mary Upp (JWD's great grandmother): silhouette (Box 186)
      - Other relatives (Box 186)
      - Unidentified [old family photographs?] (Box 186)
    - JWD at various places and events
      - JWD at Union College (Box 187)
      - JWD at the inauguration of William Edwards Stevenson as President of Oberlin College (Box 187)
      - JWD at Columbia University (Box 187)
    - JWD campaign photographs (Box 187)
    - JWD and others (Box 187)
    - Pictures of others
      - JWD's Washington and Lee classmates, faculty (Box 187)
      - [T. Fitzpatrick?] (Box 187)
      - C. A. Graves (Box 187)
      - E. M. House (Box 187)
      - [H.U. Jacoway?] (Box 187)
      - The Hon. Wallace Nesbitt (Box 187)
      - Andrew J. Peters (Box 187)
      - Frank L. Polk (Box 187)
      - Lord and Lady Reading (Box 187)
      - Shaw of Dunfermline, Thomas Shaw (Box 187)
      - Oscar W. Underwood (Box 187)
      - J. Carl Vance (Box 187)
      - J. Butler Wright (Box 187)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Churches and public buildings (Box 187)
      - Fishing trips (Box 187)
      - Landscapes (Box 187)
      - Houses (Box 187)
    - Unidentified (Box 187)
    - Unsorted snapshots (Box 187)
  - Large size photographs
    - JWD and family
      - JWD (Box 188)
      - Mrs. John W. Davis (Box 188)
      - Davis family groupings (Box 188)
      - John J. Davis (JWD's father) (Box 188)
    - JWD at various places and events
      - American Delegation-War Prisoner's Mission (Box 188)
      - Board meetings (Box 188)
      - JWD's eightieth-birthday party (Box 188)
    - JWD campaign photographs (Box 189)
    - JWD and others (Box 189)
    - Pictures of others
      - JWD's Washington and Lee classmates (Box 189)
      - Robert E. Lee: photographs of portrait and memorial (Box 189)
      - Samuel B. Pettingill (Box 189)
      - Cuthbert W. Pound (Box 189)
  - Scrapbooks of newspaper clippings
    - No. 1, 1910-1916 (Box 190)
    - No. 2, 1918-1921 (Box 190)
    - No. 3, 1924 (Box 190)
    - No. 4, 1934 (Box 191)
    - No. 5, 1940s (Box 191)
    - No. 6, 1913-1918 (Box 191)
  - Scrapbooks of photographs
    - "Our Vacation" pictorial story of an outing in the Maine woods … "1917" (Box 191)
    - Reviewing troops in France, 1919 (Box 191)
    - Photographs of the village of Sulgrave, presented by the Sulgrave Institution, 1921 (Box 191)
    - Commemorative scrapbook of 1924 presidential nomination (Box 191)
  - Drawings and posters (Box 192)
  - Facsimile manuscripts (Box 192)
  - Oversize photographs (Box 192)
  - Placques (Box 192)
  - Printer's engraving blocks (Box 192)
  - Survey maps (Box 192)
  - Loving Cup, 1924 Sep 15 (Box 192A)
  - Catalog of correspondence
    - Series A: (1918-1928)-1955
      - Outgoing, A-W (Box 193)
      - Incoming, A-M (Box 193)
      - Incoming, N-Z (Box 194)
    - Series B: (1929-1938)-1955
      - Outgoing, A-Z (Box 195)
      - Incoming, A-Z (Box 196)
  - Oversize
    - Certificates and diplomas (Box 196)
      See: box 198
- Oversize Materials, Series XII
  - Folios
    - Correspondence [from Series I and II], 1885, 1894, 1899-1900, 1919-1921 (Box 197)
    - Certificates and diplomas [from Series XI], 1901-1902, 1921-1939, 1947, 1952-1953 (Box 198)
- Additional Material, Accession 1997-M-073
  - Presidential campaign [printed material], 1924
    - Davis, John W. [speeches] (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Democratic National Committee (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - La Follette, Robert (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - People's National Independent Ticket [folio containing poster and ballot] (Box 2)
- Additional Material, Accession 1998-M-048
  - Audiocassette tape of John W. Davis speaking at dinner at Waldorf Astoria given by Isidore Kresel for Davis and Theodore Kiendl, 1935 April 6; 1 (Box 1)
    See: Audio tape AC20 [AC20 is a master audio tape which may not be used by patrons. Duplicate copies must be made from which user copies are produced for patron use]
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.